<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R package on fboehm.us</title>
    <link>/tags/r-package/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R package on fboehm.us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>frederick.boehm@gmail.com (Frederick J. Boehm)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>frederick.boehm@gmail.com (Frederick J. Boehm)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-package/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>qtl2pleio on CRAN</title>
      <link>/blog/qtl2pleio-on-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>frederick.boehm@gmail.com (Frederick J. Boehm)</author>
      <guid>/blog/qtl2pleio-on-cran/</guid>
      <description>CRAN now hosts the packages qtl2pleio and gemma2. qtl2pleio performs a d-variate, d-QTL scan over a select genomic region. gemma2 is used by qtl2pleio for the inference of multivariate variance components.
They can be installed with:
install.packages(&amp;quot;qtl2pleio&amp;quot;) The statistical model that qtl2pleio fits for each d-tuple of markers (or pseudomarkers) is
\[ vec(Y) = Xvec(B) + vec(G) + vec(E) \] where \(Y\) is a n by d matrix of d traits (for each of n subjects), X is a dn by df block-diagonal matrix of founder allele probabilities, B is a f by d matrix of allele effects for each of d traits, G is a n by d matrix of polygenic random effects, and E is a n by d matrix of random errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package site incorporation into my personal website</title>
      <link>/blog/r-package-site-incorporation-into-my-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 10:01:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>frederick.boehm@gmail.com (Frederick J. Boehm)</author>
      <guid>/blog/r-package-site-incorporation-into-my-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Overview I’ve been developing the R package qtl2pleio. It’s now at a stage where others can use it. I recently found the R package pkgdown, which allows developers to build, in an automated fashion, websites for their packages. I posted an entry on pkgdown earlier this year. I now wish to communicate my strategy for incorporating the package site into my personal website, https://fboehm.us. I write this primarily as a reminder to myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>